Guide to the Ruth A. Roland Manuscripts MC.357
New York University Archives
Ruth A. Roland Manuscripts
1963-circa 2017
New York University Archives
Roland, Ruth A., 1922-
Roland, Richard R.
MC.357
1 linear feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 2 folders in shared housing
Ruth Aileen Roland (1922-2017) was a political scientist and educator. Roland graduated from Northeastern University in 1958. She earned her Master of Arts (1963) and Ph.D. (1969) from the New York University Graduate School of Arts and Science. She served as a professor of political science at Georgia Southwestern College from 1966-1990. The Ruth A. Roland Manuscripts (dated 1963-circa 2017) consist of materials written by Ruth A. Roland, including manuscripts in various stages and copies of the published works Interpreters as Diplomats: A Diplomatic History of the Role of Interpreters in World Politics (1999) and Translating World Affairs (1982). The collection also includes Roland's New York University diplomas and a Founders Day Award certificate.
Scope and Contents
The Ruth A. Roland Manuscripts (dated 1963-circa 2017) consist of materials written by Ruth A. Roland, including manuscripts in various stages and copies of the published works Interpreters as Diplomats: A Diplomatic History of the Role of Interpreters in World Politics (1999) and Translating World Affairs (1982). The collection also includes Roland's New York University diplomas and a Founders Day Award certificate.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged alphabetically by title, followed by diplomas and an award certificate.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Richard Roland, nephew of Ruth A. Roland, in January 2021; the accession number associated with this gift is 2022.020.
Biographical Note
Ruth Aileen Roland (1922-2017) was a political scientist and educator. Roland graduated from Northeastern University in 1958. She earned her Master of Arts (1963) and Ph.D. (1969) from the New York University Graduate School of Arts and Science. Roland published two books: Interpreters as Diplomats: A Diplomatic History of the Role of Interpreters in World Politics (1999) and Translating World Affairs (1982). She served as a professor of political science at Georgia Southwestern College from 1966-1990.
Manuscripts; Political science.; Political scientists; Women political scientists; Roland, Richard R.
- Biedermeier Manuscript, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Dance of Death Manuscript, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Degenerate Art Manuscript, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- En Pointe Manuscript, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Fu Dog, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- More than Meets the Eye: Deep-Diving in the Arts Dictionary, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Haikunimals, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- Interpreters as Diplomats: A Diplomatic History of the Role of Interpreters in World Politics, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Kit-Cat Manuscript, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mauve Manuscript, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Parergon Manuscript, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Psychadelic Manuscript, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Translating World Affairs, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Multiple Manuscripts, circa 1960s-2017 (Box 2, Folder 5-9)
- Diplomas, 1963-1969 (Box Shared University Archives 131, Folder 6)
- Founders Day Award, 1970 (Box Shared University Archives 131, Folder 7)